#### **Curriculum Vitae**

# REETTA RANTA



mob +358 50 5741 841 email reetta@poweranimalpublishing.com web reettaranta.com social LinkedIn Facebook

# address

Twitter Instagram

Marjatantie 21 00560 HELSINKI

#### **Profile**

I am a visiory minded leader producer, storyteller, media consultant and coach. I have worked for several start ups and media companies including Power Animals United, Rabbit Films, Finnish Broadcasting Company Yle, New Me, Basso Radio, Sulake and Razorfish. I work with individuals and companies who are looking to express a deeper calling in this life. Combining my almost 20 years background in international media and various leadership roles into love, nature, storytelling and the magical with a mix of modern coaching and ancient spiritual practices I lead companies and people to their calling and success.

I am also a volunteer and a director of the executive board at <u>Women's Bank</u> microlending charity organization.

#### My main skills

leadership | coaching | facilitating | brands | concepts | writing | performing

## Recommendations/testimonials:

"Reetta sees things that the rest of us aren't able to see. She has been an invaluable help to us at the Rabbit Films."

#### Jarno Laasala

Partner, Dudeson & Chairman of the Board / Rabbit Films

"Reetta is Urban Shaman; a rare talent with horizontal understanding on cocreativity, digital storytelling, budgeting and how to get things done. On top of her broad skill set, Reetta brings in the magic and warmth."

## Risto Kuulasmaa

Head of Television & Online at Yle Finland

I have had a wonderful chance to receive Reetta's coaching as a writer, producer and tv-host at Rabbit Films. Reetta is a highly professional, kind, demanding, solution-focused and soulful mentor and coach. Although I have had a few good coaching experiences during my professional career I have no patience for trendy "life coaches" and their empty words. Reetta is something different. She helps, encourages and asks the right questions. Reetta is open minded, positive and intelligent woman, whose words, tools and keys would do good for anybody."

# Jenni Pääskysaari

TV host, writer & producer

Reetta is a great professional in digital design, branding and business. I have worked with Reetta in Sulake and in YLE, and in both places Reetta has done more than great work in concept design, brand development and project/team leading. She is also always happy and really easy to work with.

## Sami Lanu

Digital Strategist and Lecturer

"Reetta was part of the management development program I created and presided over at Razorfish called Catapult. She is smart, talented and a born leader."

## **Richard Titus**

Entrepreneurial senior executive (Richard managed Reetta indirectly at Razorfish)

Reetta is very versatile, smart and positive professional.

#### Aapo Kyrölä

Software Engineer at Facebook (Aapo managed Reetta indirectly at Sulake)

curriculum vitae

# REETTA RANTA

## Work experience

# POWER ANIMALS UNITED LTD

Producer, Director of Strategy and Story 09/2014 » current

Main focus area:

Content and strategy development for new projects, including concepting, packaging, and producing the TV series <u>Metsien kätkemä</u> for YLE together with <u>Flatlight Creative House</u> and <u>Retkipaikka.fi</u>.

# **RABBIT FILMS LTD**

**Director of Strategy & Spirituality** 03/2013 » as an external consult since 09/2013 *Main focus area:* 

Helping the company to clarify its purpose and the ways to serve the world based on its calling. Providing strategical, mental and spiritual coaching for employees and directors.

## Country Manager 07/2010 » 03/2013

Main focus area:

Responsible for business development, global management for The Dudesons brand development, overall communications and digital strategy. Worked also with brand extension projects like books, games, animation, sponsorships and M&L.

# **NEW ME OY** 04/2011-2014

## Co-founder and owner, Creative Director/CEO

Main focus area:

Responsible for business development, storytelling, mobile applications and digital strategy.

# LAUANTAI OY 9/2008 » current

Co-founder and owner, Executive Producer of following projects:

Olga & Pamela, interactive comedy series (scriptwriter, producer), for Yle 2010 & 2011

Pirjo, multi-channel strory-music-comedy-mix, (scriptwriter, singer & songwriter)

# **BASSO RADIO** 12/2013 - 05/2014

Radio host for Ipanapa Radio

# **N2 MARKETING** 05/2010 - 06/2010

Strategist/Planner

YLE (Finnish Broadcasting Company) 1/2007 – 12/2014 Radio host for Uudenkansanmusiikki 04/2014 - 12/2014 Yle Radio Suomi

## curriculum vitae

# REETTA RANTA

## Head of New Media Development 1/2010 - 05/2010

Main focus area:

Responsible for children, youth & family genre in yle.fi

#### Roles & responsibilities:

Strategic planning, budgeting, partner management, superior of the production and content production team, overall service responsibility in digital area within YLE children, youth & family brands, such as Pikku Kakkonen, Galaxi, Summeri and Olotila.

#### Other responsibilities:

Member of the YLE New media management team

### Executive Producer 8 / 2008 - 12/2009

Main focus area:

New media services for children and youth

#### Roles & responsibilities:

Strategic planning, budgeting, partner management, superior of the production and content production team, overall service responsibility in digital area within YLE children & youth brands, such as Pikku Kakkonen, Galaxi and Summeri.

# Concept Producer, Concept Team Leader 1/2007-7/2008

Main focus area:

New media services for children and youth, pop culture, entertainment and channels YleX and YLE Extra

# Roles & responsibilities:

Project management, writing and concept design + guideline production in multichannel and online productions, such as yle.fi/pikkukakkonen, yle.fi/extra, ylex.fi, yle.fi/pop.

Team leader for the group of 9 Concept Producers and Concept Designers.

# SULAKE CORPORATION 5/2001 - 12/2006

## Creative Director, Sales and Business Development

08/2004 - 12/2006

# Roles & responsibilities:

Concept design, writing and guideline production in global brand extension projects, such as Habbo animation, merchandising and licensing (including clothes, accessories, publications etc.)

## Brand Director and Design Team leader 2002 - 08/2004

Roles & responsibilities:

- global brand strategy, guideline production, internal & external training
- global marketing, pr & communications strategies and execution
- Sulake Design Team management
- scriptwriting, concept design and copywriting for Habbo web and marketing

## Country Manager | habbo.fi 05/2001 - 2003

## Roles & responsibilities:

- financial coordination, partner management and ad sales

#### curriculum vitae

# REETTA RANTA

- Habbo.fi team management, content and community management
- concept design and copywriting for Habbo web and marketing

#### Other:

Minor share holder, member of the management team 2001-2002

# **RAZORFISH LTD** 05/1998 - 04/2001

# Content Manager & Content Skillset Leader

## Roles & responsibilities:

Content design, strategy and management in web and mobile applications, guideline production, copywriting, sales & marketing, recruiting, coaching, internal & external communication.

## Other:

Member of skillset leader group, member of international Razorfish Creative Council, member of international Razorfish leadership trainee program.

## **Board experience**

Naisten Pankki, chairman of the board of directors Lauantai Oy, chairman of the board New Me Oy, chairman of the board Hello Island Entertainment Oy, chairman of the board Sotungin kyläyhdistys, member of the board (2011–2013)

## **Education**

## University of Art and Design, Helsinki, graduated 05/2009

program: Master of Arts in New Media focus area: Interactive Audiovisual Narrative

# University of Helsinki 1995 -2004

major: Finnish language, final thesis approved 2004

minors: sociology, film and tv science

# University of Jyväskylä 1994-1995

major: communications (intercultural communications & communication in organizations)

#### Other education:

International Coaching Certification, WeCreate 2012 – 2013
Coaching Program for Managers, YLE 2009
Coaching Program for Managers, YLE 2008
Producer Program, YLE 2007
Leadership Trainee Program Catapult, Razorfish 2000
Project Management, Proteus 2000

# Language skills

Finnish, English (fluent), Swedish (limited skills), Germany (basic knowledge)

# Other experience

Dina.tv, experimental tv channel (producer, scriptwriter), 2006

Mobile Continent art exhibition (wap design, voice service design, content design), 2000

Paperworks (copywriting, marketing assistance, sales), 1996-1998

Freelancer (writer, teacher, consultant, proof reader, actress, waitress, guide etc.), 1994 –2002

PULP, student tv at University of Jyväskylä (journalist, camera man, edit, scriptwriter), 1994-1995

## **Examples of publications and scriptwriting:**

- Metsien kätkemä f
- Naisten Pankki ads, example: Nainen on naiselle #bisnesenkeli https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=8WT8Bpo90ME
- #lovemilla format bible, Yle 2014
- Books: Part of the writing team in following books:
  - Metsien kätkemä (coming fall 2016 from Gummerus)
  - Duudsonit Jekkukirja
  - Duudsonit 100 tapaa pelastua tylsyydeltä
  - Habbon käsikirja
  - Just another day the story of Habbo Hotel
- Several ads, guidelines/bibles and online services during 1999–2015 for different clients
- Olga & Pamela, interactive online tv & radio comedy series (scriptwriter, producer),
   Yle 2010 & 2011, examples: <a href="http://areena.yle.fi/tv/1272452">http://areena.yle.fi/tv/1272452</a>
- The Dudeson ads, example: Galaxy Xcover terapiassa Osa 3 https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=pISb7FDq-xY

# **Grants and stipends**

2010–2016 several grants secured for Rabbit Films LTD (Ministry of Culture and Education, Finnish Funding Agency for Innovation (TEKES)

2015 AVEK / Pilot episode for Metsien kätkemä

2011 AVEK / Digital Demos, 23 000 €: Vojo iPhone application

2008 AVEK / Digital Demos, 15 000 €: Olga & Pamela, interactive comedy series, (production)

2007 AVEK / Digital Demos, 2000 €: Olga & Pamela, interactive comedy series, (scriptwriting)

## **Awards & Honorable mentions**

# **VUODEN HUIPUT**

2007 Member of the Jury, Digital media

2004 Silver (Hopeahuippu, julkaisugrafiikka)

Work: "Just another day – the story of Habbo Hotel" (Habbo book)

Role: scriptwriting, concept design

2002 Honorable mention (kunniamaininta)

Work: Mountain Dew Campaign (an online campaign inside Habbo Hotel)

Role: Concept design, project management

2000 Silver (Hopeahuippu)

Work: Hiff.fi (Helsinki International Film Festival web site)

Role: Concept design, copywriting

## **OTHER**

2008 KOURA: Main prize at Children and Youth category - yle.fi/pikkukakkonen

Role: Concept design, project management

2007 Grand One: Grand Prix - YLE New Media

2007 Grand One: Honorable mention in Best infodesign

Work: yle.fi

Role: Concept design

2004 Grand One - UOMA Tekijäpalkinto

2003 RE: THE BIG ONE

Work: Mountain Dew Campaign / Habbo Hotel

Role: Concept design, project management

2003 Prix Möbius Nordica: Education

Work: Infobus HUBU at Habbo Hotel (EOPH ry)

Role: Concept design, project management

2002 Media & Message: Education and motivation, bronze

Work: Elämä On Parasta Huumetta ry: HUBU / Habbo Hotel

Role: Concept design, project management

2002 RE: THE BIG ONE: Best cross media concept and Best online campaign

Work: Elämä On Parasta Huumetta ry: HUBU / Habbo Hotel

Role: Concept design, project management

2002 RE: THE BIG ONE: Information design, gold

Work: JCDecaux.fi

Role: Concept design, copywriting

2001 RE:spekt March 2001: internet sites, gold

Work: JCDecaux.fi

Role: Concept design, copywriting

2001 Media & Message, bronze

Work: JCDecaux.fi

Role: Concept design, copywriting

1998 M&M Grand Prix, best design

Work: Spray-Razorfish home pages Role: Concept design, copywriting